A Guide to the JDR 3rd Fund records FA081
Rockefeller Archive Center
JDR 3rd Fund records
1956-1979, bulk 1963-1979
1963-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
JDR 3rd Fund
Arts in Education Program (U.S.)
FA081
118.18 Cubic Feet 311 document cases
Arrangement note
The JDR 3rd Fund records are divided into fourteen series, as follows:
Series 1 - Youth Task Force - General Correspondence Series 2 - Youth Task Force - Publications Series 3 - Youth Task Force - Yankelovich Studies Series 4 - Philanthropy Series 5 - Bicentennial Project Series 6 - Other Projects Series 7 - "The JDR 3rd Fund and Asia, 1963-1975" Series 8 - English Language Teaching in Japan Series 9 - Asian Cultural Program Series 10 - Arts in Education Program - Jane Remer Files Series 11 - Arts in Education Program - Kathryn Bloom Files Series 12 - General Records Series 13 - Miscellaneous Files Series 1040 - Photographs
Series 1-9 and 12 reflect the order of the records upon their arrival at the Rockefeller Archive Center. Series 10 and 11, however, have been rearranged to create coherent administration, project, and contact files.
Biographical/Historical note
Incorporated on September 17, 1963, with the stated purpose "to stimulate, encourage, promote, and support activities important to human welfare," the JDR 3rd Fund was conceived as the vehicle by which John D. Rockefeller 3rd could address his varied interests in fields not served by such organizations as The Population Council or The Asia Society. Mr. Rockefeller acted as President of the Fund from its establishment until his death on July 10, 1978.
Under its broad charter, the Fund engaged in three major programs: The Asian Cultural Program, The Arts in Education Program, and the Youth Task Force.
From 1963 until 1967, the Asian Cultural Program was the only activity of the Fund. Under the leadership of Datus C. Smith, Jr. and Porter A. McCray, this program operated throughout the Asian continent from Japan through Afghanistan. It promoted East-West cultural understanding through three main types of activity. Individual scholars and performing artists attempting exchanges between the two traditions received fellowships. Institutional grants were also given to aid in preserving native Asian cultural traditions through such activities as archaeological expeditions, library support, preservation of art work, and publications. The Program also sponsored tours by performing artists and exhibitions of art work in order to increase cross-cultural appreciation among the general public. Upon the dissolution of the Fund in 1979, these activities were continued by a new corporation, The Asian Cultural Council.
The Arts in Education Program was established in September 1967 in response to the 1965 Rockefeller Panel Report on the Performing Arts. In the words of Mr. Rockefeller, "The Fund's objectives in establishing the Arts in Education Program is to make the arts an integral part of our educational system at all grade levels." Directed by Kathryn Bloom and her associates Richard Grove, Jack Morrison, Gene C. Wenner, and Jane Remer, the Program operated on three levels. Pilot projects, such as those at University City, Missouri, and Mineola, New York, were established in receptive school systems to provide models which could be widely adapted elsewhere. Particular attention was placed on designing curriculum tools to integrate the arts into all phases of classroom learning, mostly through the research of CEMREL (Central Midwestern Regional Educational Laboratory). Finally, pooling of ideas and talents was encouraged through consortia such as the League of Cities for the Arts in Education and the Ad Hoc Coalition of States, both of which received financial support and leadership through the Fund. These activities continued until July 1979.
The Youth Task Force was created by the Fund in October 1970. It was designed to promote collaborative efforts between the youth of the 1970s and establishment leaders in business and the professions. Under the direction of Jerry J. Swift, the Task Force sponsored a series of dialogues between groups of young adults and older figures, held in Minneapolis, Minnesota; Cleveland, Ohio; Jackson, Mississippi; and San Francisco, California. When these meetings demonstrated a basis for cooperation, the Task Force sought to provide technical assistance for activities in which both elements could join, such as environmental and health service programs. Between 1970 and 1974, the Task Force also sponsored a series of surveys of youth attitudes which were conducted by Daniel Yankelovich, Inc. and resulted in a number of publications. The Youth Task Force was disbanded in July 1974.
The Fund also undertook a number of short-term projects not covered by the three main programs. Chief of these was the Bicentennial Project, an effort to coordinate the participation of the private sector in this national celebration by relating it to contemporary problems. Other interests of the Fund included the teaching of English in Japan, domestic volunteer service in Indonesia, and studying the impact of private philanthropy on American life.
Upon the death of Mr. Rockefeller in 1978, leadership of the Fund passed to his wife, Mrs. Blanchette Rockefeller. Under her direction, the Fund fulfilled its obligations for the ensuing fiscal year and was dissolved in July 1979.
Scope and Contents note
The records of the JDR 3rd Fund consist of correspondence, reports, publications, administrative material, financial records, records of meetings, and a wide array of non-textual material documenting the activities of the Fund's various programs. These records also contain large contact files, consisting of correspondence, brochures, and records of meetings related to organizations with which the Fund had no grant relationship.
While the records of the Youth Task Force, Arts in Education Program, and of miscellaneous programs remain intact, those of the Asian Cultural Program have been retained by its successor organization, the Asian Cultural Council. Consequently, only a small amount of this material has been retained as part of the JDR 3rd Fund Records.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 3B 10
Arts -- Asia; Performing arts; College students; College students -- Political activity; Asia; Arts; Education; Philanthropy -- United States; United States; Philanthropy; Japan
- Youth Task Force - General Correspondence, 1969-1974; 01; 19 Cubic Feet 38 document cases
  Scope and Contents note
  This series is an alphabetical file containing correspondence, reports, publications, memoranda, and grant files relating to the activities of the Youth Task Force and its contacts with other organizations.
  - Abraxas, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Action, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aerosol, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Air Force Academy Foundation, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alberty, Elsie J., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alliance for Labor Action, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Assembly - Correspondence, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Assembly - Reports, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Bar Association, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Civil Liberties Union Foundation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Federation of Government Employees, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Jewish Committee - Reports on "America's Young Workers", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Society for Public Administration, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Standard, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Appalachian Leaders in Community Outreach, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Appalachian Leaders in Community Outreach - Proposal, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Archives of International Change, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ascension, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Asia Society, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Asiatic Revolution, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Associated Students of the University of California at Davis, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Association Internationale des Etudants en Sciences Economiques et Commerciales - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Association Internationale des Etudants en Sciences Economiques et Commerciales - Conference Material, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Association of Black Foundation Executives, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Association of Student Governments, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Association of Voluntary Action Scholars, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bank Street College of Education - Report, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Barker, Mark, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Barnard College Women's Center, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bernstein Foundation, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Beyond the Scranton Report, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bicentennial, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bicentennial Youth Conference, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
  - Binder, Charles E., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Black, Molly, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Black P Stone Nation - Literature and Background Material, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Black P Stone Nation - Chicago Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Black Students' Summer Program of the National Urban League - Report, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - The Blue Gargoyle - Chicago Project (Pete Stodder), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Bond, Julian, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Boys' Club of New York, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Break Free, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Broadcast Industry Conference, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Brown, Dyke (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Bunche, Ralph - Development Fund Committee Speech, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Business Council for International Understanding, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Business Executive's Fund for National Priorities, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Business Leaders' Meeting (December 17, 1970) and Follow-up, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Business and Society - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Business and Society - Publications, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Business Today/Business Tomorrow - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Business Today/Business Tomorrow - Publications, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Businessmen's Educational Fund, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Buxton, Brenda, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous (C) (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - California, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Candidates for Panels, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Center for Analysis of Public Issues - Publications, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Center for Analysis of Public Issues - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Center for Community Action, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 64-66)
  - Center for Community Change, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Center for Responsive Journalism, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Chase Manhattan, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Chicago - Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Chicago - Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Children's Services Council, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Chinese Youth Council, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Church of Cosmic Liberation, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Cincinnati Experience, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Council on International Relations and United Nations Affairs (CIRUNA), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Citizen's Communications Center, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Citizen's Communications Center - Reports, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Community Improvement Through Youths (CITY), Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Clark Foundation, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Clearing House for Youth, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Cleveland Dialogs, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 82-83)
  - Cole National Corporation, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - College for Human Services, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Columbia University - Business Action, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Committee of United People, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Common Cause, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Community Arts Workshop, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Conference Board, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Conference Board - Publications, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Congressional Action Fund, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Connecticut River Valley - Speech and Publicity, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Connecticut River Valley - Reaction to Student Turndown of Grant, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Connecticut Valley Committee, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - CONTINUE, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Coro Foundation, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Corporate Responsibility, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Council of New York Law Associates - Newsletter, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Council on Economic Priorities - Reports, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Council on Foundations, 1972-1975 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Miscellaneous (D) (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Delancy Street Foundation, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Demography, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Dialogs - Analysis by Facilitators, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Dialogs - General, 1971-1974 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Dialogs - Miscellany, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Domestic Action, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Drug Abuse Council, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Dallas Young Adult Institute (DYAI), 1971 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Dynamy, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Miscellaneous (E) (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Earth Action Week, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - East Kentucky Health Services Center, Inc., 1972 (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Eastern Washington Legal Services, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Education for Involvement Corporation, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Environic Foundation International, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Environmental Action, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Environmental Clearing House - Grassroots Project, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Environmental Resources, Inc., 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Executive High School Internships, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Miscellaneous (F) (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Field Foundation, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Five Colleges, Inc., 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    Grant #EC-7176-5
  - Ford Foundation, 1969-1973 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Foundations, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 128)
  - Foundations - Printed Matter, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 129)
  - The Fourth Estate, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  - Friends of the Earth, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - Fund for the City of New York, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - Funding, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - Futures Conditional, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - Miscellaneous (G) (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - Georgia Plan, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Goals for Dallas, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 137-138)
  - Miscellaneous (H) (Box 13, Folder 139)
  - Haft, Steven, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Harlem Youth Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Hartford, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 142-143)
  - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Health/Pac, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Hollow Organization, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Miscellaneous (I) (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Independent Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 148)
  - Inner City Fund, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 149)
  - INROADS, Inc., 1972 (Box 14, Folder 150)
  - Institute for Social Resources, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 151)
  - Institute for the Study of Health and Society, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Internship Programs, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Involvement Corps, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Iowa Wesleyan Response to Social Involvement, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - Irish Question, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - Miscellaneous (J) (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - Jackson Dialogs - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - Jackson Dialogs - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 159-161)
  - Jackson Dialogs - Contacts and File Cards, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 162)
  - Jaycees, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 163)
  - Joint Foundation Support, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - Joseph Hill Associates, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 165-166)
  - Miscellaneous (K) (Box 16, Folder 166A)
  - Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Foundation, 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 167)
  - Kiley, Mary E., 1962-1971 (Box 16, Folder 168)
  - K-O Associations of Boston, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 169)
  - Miscellaneous (L) (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Law Students Civil Rights Research Council, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Lawyers' Military Advisory Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 172)
  - Leadership Training Project - Pittsburgh, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - League of Women Voters, 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 174)
  - Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 175)
  - Living Learning Center, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 176)
  - Los Angeles Public Law Center, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 177)
  - Louisville Dialog, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 178)
  - Louisville Dialog - Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Louisville Dialog - File Cards, undated (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Henry Luce Foundation, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - Miscellaneous (M) (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - Manual for Youth Groups, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - Maryland Student Union, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 184)
  - Massachusetts Public Interest Research Group (MASSPIRG), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 185)
  - Metrocenters, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 186)
  - Minnesota Public Interest Research Group (MPIRG), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 187)
  - Minnesota Union of College Students, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 188)
  - Mississippi Council on Human Relations, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 189)
  - Mott, Stewart, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - Miscellaneous (N) (Box 17, Folder 191)
  - National Affiliation of Concerned Business Students, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - Nader's Raiders, 1970-1973 (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - National Association of Black Students, undated (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - National Center for Voluntary Action, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 195)
  - National Child Labor Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 196)
  - National Committee on Resources for Youth, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 197)
  - National Conference on Citizenship, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - National Council of Churches, 1972-1974 (Box 18, Folder 199)
  - National Dialog Conference, Palo Alto, June 29-30, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 200)
  - National Federation of Settlement and Neighborhood Centers (NFS) Youth Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - National Information Bureau, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 202)
  - National Student Association - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 203)
    Grant #B-71114-5
  - National Student Association - Publications, 1970-1974 (Box 19, Folder 204)
  - National Student Association - Center for Educational Reform, 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 205)
  - National Student Association - Gay Student Center, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 206)
  - National Student Association - Women's Center, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 207)
  - National Student Lobby, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 208)
  - National Training Laboratories Institute for Applied Behavioral Science, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 209)
  - National Urban League, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 210)
  - National VISTA Alliance, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 211)
  - Neighborhood Alternatives Program, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 212)
  - Newman Commission on Higher Education, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 213)
  - New Schools Exchange, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 214)
  - New World Foundation, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 215)
  - Newsweek, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 216)
  - The Norman Foundation, 1969-1972 (Box 21, Folder 217)
  - Northwest Fund for Justice, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 218)
  - North Carolina Internship Office - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 219)
  - North Carolina Internship Office - Publications, 1970-1972 (Box 21, Folder 220)
  - Number Nine (New Haven, Connecticut), 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 221-222)
  - Miscellaneous (O) (Box 22, Folder 223)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity (OEO)/Project Map Youth Development Program, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 224)
  - Ohio Governor's School Program, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 225)
  - Open Presidency Task Force, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 226)
  - Open Presidency Task Force - Publications, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 227)
  - Organization Response, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 228)
  - Our House (University of Massachusetts), 1971 (Box 22, Folder 229)
  - Miscellaneous (P) (Box 22, Folder 230)
  - Player's Workshop, Inc., 1970 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - Political Action, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 232)
  - President's Council on Youth Opportunity, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 233-234)
  - Press Foundation of Asia, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 235)
  - Primary Shelter, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 236)
  - Princeton Winter/Summer in the City, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 237)
  - Priority One, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 238)
  - Project Interface - Proposals, 1971-1973 (Box 23, Folder 239-240)
  - Project Interface - Materials, 1970-1973 (Box 24, Folder 241-243)
  - Project on Corporate Responsibility, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 244)
  - Project One, undated (Box 24, Folder 245)
  - Project Runnyside, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 246)
  - Project Youth, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 247)
  - President's Science Advisory Committee (PSAC) Panel on Youth, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 248)
  - Public Processes Foundation, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 249)
  - Quality of Working Life, 1972-1974 (Box 24, Folder 250)
  - Miscellaneous (R) (Box 25, Folder 251)
  - Ralston-Purina Company, 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 252)
  - Resumes - Staff and Consultants (A-Z) (Box 25, Folder 253)
  - Resumes - Contracts (A-Z) (Box 25, Folder 254)
  - Resumes - Contracts (A-Z) (Box 25, Folder 255)
  - Ripon Society, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 256)
  - Rockefeller Brothers' Fund, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 257)
  - Rockefeller Family Fund, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 258)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 259)
  - Rockefeller, John D. 3rd - Biography, 1969-1974 (Box 25, Folder 260)
  - JDR 3rd Fund - Tax Exemption Letters, 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 261)
  - Rosenberg Foundation, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 261A)
  - Rosendahl, William, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 262)
  - Ruder and Finn, 1969-1972 (Box 26, Folder 263)
  - Regional Young Adult Project, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 264)
  - Miscellaneous (S) (Box 26, Folder 265)
  - San Francisco Dialogs, 1971-1974 (Box 26, Folder 266-267)
  - San Francisco Dialogs - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 268)
  - San Francisco Dialogs - Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 269)
  - San Francisco - Organizations, 1969-1973 (Box 27, Folder 270-271)
  - Sanctuary, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 272)
  - Scholarship, Education and Defense Fund for Racial Equality, Inc. (SEDFRE), 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 273)
  - Shuman, James, undated (Box 27, Folder 274)
  - Source, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 275)
  - Stanford Research Institute, 1967-1971 (Box 27, Folder 276)
  - Stern Fund, 1969-1973 (Box 28, Folder 277)
  - Stone Foundation, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 278)
  - Student Advisory Committee on International Affairs - Project Dialogue, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 279)
  - Student American Medical Association - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 280)
  - Student American Medical Association - Publications, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 281)